15 minutes,15 hours...
inside the o.r.,
the best surgeons  make time fly.
outside the o.r.,however,
time takes pleasure  in kicking our asses.
for even the strongest of us,it seems to play tricks--
slowing down,hovering...
until it freezes...
leaving us stuck in a moment,
unable to move  in one direction or the other.
izzie.izzie. come on.
okay,she's been in there all night. we have to do something.
- yeah.
- yeah.yeah.
why are you all looking at me?
well,this is familiar territory for you.
there is nothing familiar about this.
unfamiliar.
denny died.
the man she loves died.
yeah,but you're all dark and twisty inside.
"dark and twisty"?
the mother with the alzheimer's thing
and the father you don't talk to.
and the teruila thing and the inappropriate men thing.
you are dark and twisty inside,meredith,and now izzie is dark and twisty inside.
so all of a sudden i'm the president of people with crappy lives?
seriously,we have to do something.
someone has to go in there.
the seven years  you spend as a surgical resident
will be the best  and worst of your life.
look around you.
say hello  to your competition.
hi. izzie stevens.washington.
hey. alex karev.ia.
this is nice,right? they threw a mixer for the new interns.
yeah.
it's just an excuse to get us all happy and drunk before they torture us.
- what program are you in?
- surgery.
- seriously?
- seriously.
what?
i-i picked you for gynie or peds or something.
you don't think i can be a surgeon?
i can be a surgeon.
surgery's hard-core.
i'm hard-core.
you won't last the first year,babe.
hey,izzie. what?
maybe you should...
ch-change your clothes.
maybe you'd want to wear something more comfortable.
- stop it.
- i know.
- izzie--
- stop it.i mean it.stop...talking.
there is nothing to talk about. do you understand me?
there is nothing to discuss.
i'm so sorry.
yeah.yeah,me,too.
- so you're a surgeon.
- yes.
usually they don't send a surgeon for this.
what--what do we need to-- how do i do this?
how do we do this?
you just gotta i.d.the body before i take him to the funeral home...
so i don't take the wrong guy.
that happens?
you wouldn't believe how many times i take the wrong guy.
th-that's him.that's... denny duruette.
great. load him up.and sign.
when's the funeral?
no funeral.
the family asked to have the body sent to memphis.
uh,wait,wait,wait,wait.
i'm sorry.
i'm so sorry.
why are we making sandwiches again?
it's what you do when someone dies. you cook.
yeah,i-i know what to do when someone dies.
i am a jew.
i know food and death.
it's shivah.
is it shivah even if she's catholic?
well,shivah's what i know how to do,so...
yeah,it's shivah.
and if we're sitting shivah for denny,
then we should order in
because making sandwiches is not the same as cooking.
sandwiches are comfort food.
what's wrong with you?
everything with me is fine.
it's izzie thate're worried about.
oh,what did you do?
denny died. burke got shot.
let's just have some perspective and remember what i did is a tiny,slightly small--
whatever. spit it out.
i lost my panties last night.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
proudly presents
sync: ytet-colleen3684
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
grey's anatomy
season 3 episode 01
you back already?
oh,i never left.
i did a craniotomy on a,uh,ruptured saccular aneurysm.
i've been here all night,too.
i wanted to see the autopsy on duruette.
yeah.
have you seen meredith?
uh,dr.grey-- have you seen,uh,have you seen dr.grey?
why?
what's goin' on with you?
no,could you just--
can you get somebody to cover my rounds for me so i can take care of some stuff?
are you free,dr.shepherd?
and the pit's overcrowded with early flu season.
giselle toussaint,42-year-old woman,
unrestrained driver of a car that hit a railing.
ejected from the car.
she was--we were coming to the e.r.
we were both sick.
we couldn't shake this flu thing.
so she was better,so i let her drive.
- sir?
- omar?
giselle,honey.
where are we?
oh,yeah. are we...
- are we dancing?
- we had an accident.
we have a dural laceration. she's leaking spinal fluid.
let's get an o.r.ready,okay?
the dancing's so beautiful.
you're beautiful.
he's burning up.
all right,somebody get him a bed. let's get her up to the o.r.right away.
what's goin' on?
premature newborn found in a trash can at turner prep school.
the umbilical cord's still attached.
you didn't start an i.v.? he's dehydrated.
we couldn't find a vein.
i need to get an i.v.access.
get me an i.o.needle,
and i need a neonatal intubation kit.
olivia,go!move.now.
they pulled me from the floor. i'm just down here helping with the flu overflow.
alex,how old's that baby?
wait,wait,wait. what are you doing?
if you think i'm going to leave this sick,premature infant in the e.r.--
he has to be admitted.
- you can't just take him.
- just page addison shepherd!
page addison shepherd. tell her to meet me in the nicu.
karev.
premature newborn male with petechiae.
what's his platelet count?
- 17,000.
- 17,000?
did you transfuse platelets?
yes,but it didn't help.
- where's the mother?
- i don't know.
dr.karev...
i'm not asking you where the mother is for my health.
i expect you to use your brain.
- where is the mother?
- i don't know!
the baby was found in a trash can at a high school.
they left him in a trash can.
he's got some inner abdominal bleeding on c.t.
you want to run some more tests?
dr.shepherd?
i need a stat ultrasound and for you to infuse 2 grams of i.v.i.g.
if there is no cranial bleeding.
and then find out where the mother is.
i need to test for maternal platelet antibodies.
can't you just do surgery to fix the abdominal bleeding?
if i wanted to kill him,i could do that. damn it.
who does this?
dr.montgomery-shepherd,there are some people here about the baby.
the clot's been evacuated. are we ready to close?
i just want to make sure there are no remaining bone fragments.
how's izzie?
as well as can be expected.
it's never gets easier,you know? losing a patient.
it gets a little less...
shocking,i guess,but...
it never gets any easier.
izzie was in love with him.
denny wasn't just a patient. they were in love.
you had sex with derek in an exam room at the prom?
- yes.
- last night,you and shepherd did it?
yes.
you and mcdreamy did the nasty-nasty?
- cristina!
- i'm not judging.
i'm just trying to wrap my mind around it.
i mean,you're with finn,and he's with addison.
he's married to addison.
yeah.
well,what did derek say?
he said,"meredith,what does this mean?"
okay... he has sex with you
and he's standing there all mcguilty,
and all he has to say for himself is,
"oh,what does this mean?"
what does this mean?
i don't know.
well,are you gonna go back to finn?
uh,i-is shepherd leaving his wife?
- i just--
- meredith,hold on with both hands.
- meredith!
- mommy!
- richard,you were to tell adele.
- look,i-i can't.
- i was to tell thatcher.
- that is what we said.
- i can't do it.
that is what we agreed.
please,richard,please.
you can't leave me.
ellis,no.
richard,you can't leave me!
richard!richard!richard!
you didn't have to make an appointment to see me.
i'm your husband.
an appointment seemed to be the best way to get your undivided attention,because here you are.
- adele,listen--
- sit down.
- adele--
- sit down!
we have an appointment.
uh,chief,ex-- um,the i.d.c.is here.
we had a couple come in this morning--
derek just finished a craniotomy on the wife--but the husband,
he's got severe flu sytoms-- swollen lymph nods,buboes.
- turns out they came in contact with the plague.
- the plague?
look,i'm sorry,adele.
i-i need to deal with this.
shannon is a straight-a student.
so what,my daughter gets a b in math,
and suddenly she's birthing babies in toilet stalls?
i'm dr.montgomery-shepherd. i'm treating the newborn.
he has an emergent blood condition.
i need to know whose baby it is i'm dealing with.
yeah,we'd all like to know that.
sara... talk.
i don't know anything about any baby,mom.
none of us do.
well,one of you must know something,otherwise you and your parents wouldn't be here.
our girls--the principal said that they were the last people in the bathroom before that baby was found.
so we just thought,before the police show up...
one of you knows,and you better confess.
i don't want my lisa messed up in this.
look,the police will be here soon.
can't you just do some sort of d.n.a.test so that the rest of us can get out of here?
d.n.a.results take days,
and frankly,i'm not concerned with getting the rest of you "out of here."
if this baby isn't treated,he's going to die.
now i can do vaginal exams on each of the girls--
my daughter is 14 years old.
she's not sexually active.
and i won't have you violating her body.
you won't have it 'cause you know it's your kid.
i tell you what,you have my consent
to do whatever it takes to prove my lisa's innocent.
you are a sick bastard,you know that?
a child's life is in jeopardy here.
and it's not your consent that i need.
we didn't do anything wrong.
just because we were in there doesn't mean it's our baby.
do we look like the kind of girls who get pregnant and throw their kids into the trash?
nice work today,o'malley.
hey,did meredith go home with izzie?
yeah,cristina,too. i'm headed there now.
- yeah,me,too.
- oh,great.
it's just that,um...
i don't know if izzie's up for a lot of people.
well,i'm gonna go see meredith.
oh.okay.
- dr.shepherd?
- yes.
- dr.o'malley?
- yeah.
i'm with the i.d.c. is anyone else in this room?
no.
- you peormed the surgery on mrs.toussaint?
- yes.
she and her husband were in closeontact with a victim of the plague.
she may have been exposed.
- which means we may have been.
- yeah.
i gotta go. i can't do this.
we're waiting on the diagnosis on mrs.toussaint.
this room will be sealed off until we know the threat has been contained,and you're absolutely safe.
- you're not saying--
- you cannot leave.
you two are quarntined.
i should check in with the i.d.c.rep. you know,i have to stay on top of my hospital.
keep me posted.
hello!hello! i need help.somebody,please.
i know you can hear me.
i see you standing out there in your giant white space suit.
- sir?
- yes!
no unauthorized personnel beyond this point,ma'am.
i.d.c.regulations.
look,i know he's under quarintine,
but he is also a patient.
and i will not ignore a patient.
ah. hello out there.
thank god. thank god you can hear me.
how is my wife?
my name is dr.bailey-- miranda bailey.
your wife is out of surgery.
she's quarntined in recovery,
but she's doing fine.
now you were asking for help?
you know how many days i been in here?
it's only been a few hours.
really?
i'm losing it.
i'm losing track of time.
okay,sir,you're sweating.
i need you to sit down.
get back in the bed.
wh-what about my wife giselle?
can you find out about giselle?
like i said,sir,she came out of surgery just fine,
but i can check on her status again.
you just stay calm until i get back.
no!no,wait,wait.don't go.please.
just...
just stay a minute. please.
okay. um...
i'm staying.
omar. call me omar.
okay,omar.
i'm... i'm right here.
i brought food.
uh,george isn't here.
no,i-i know.
uh,he's in a quarntine 'cause of a-a thing.
and i was off duty and i was worried about him
and going crazy,and i thought about izzie,and so i brought food.
for the shivah.
are--are you gonna let me in?
yeah.
relax,i'm not gonna bring it up--
you and mcdreamy and the sex.
- i'm not that person.
- good.
- okay.
shivah? is it shivah if izzie's catholic?
this thing that you're doing,izzie,it's not healthy.
i mean,you gotta take off that dress.
tell me about shivah.
well,it's something you do when someone dies.
you know,we did it for my grandmother.
how does it work?
people bring over food,
family comes over.
it's supposed to help with the grieving,you know?
it honors the dead.
- sounds nice.
- yeah.
seven days of no leather shoes,
no--no work,no sex,
no sitting on things higher than a foot,
no--no shaving,no...
what?
no clean clothes.
izzie...
this doesn't have to be shivah.
you know they took his body away.
i will never see him again.
how would you feel if you never saw burke again?
so we're sitting shivah for denny.
you want to see him?
- see who?
- the baby.your baby.
it's not our baby.
i'm giving you permission to do this thing. now what's the hang-up?
the "hang-up," sir,
is that if your daughter doesn't want to do it,
i can't force her.
they're 14. they're minors.
we still have a say.
no,you don't.
if someone doesn't want to submit to a vaginal exam,
they don't have to. it's the law.
all right. that's it.
i'm taking lisa home.
you do that,sir,and i will have you arrested before you hit the parking lot.
the law isn't the only thing in play here.
if i do a vaginal exam and the girl is a virgin,
there could be bleeding,undue trauma,
not to mention emotional stress.
well,if i had to take a guess as to whose kid won't have to worry about that--
what's that supposed to mean?
it'd just be nice if karen had a curfew.
well,at least she's not a shoplifter.
oh,shannon stole one lipstick when she was 9. get over it.
i know for a fact that my lisa is a virgin.
really?
and how do you know that?
because she's only 14 years old!
they're all 14.
derek. derek listen to me.
derek,you can't do this.
derek,we have to--
- we have to talk about this.
- no,we don't.
you have to give me a chance to explain.
what are you doing?
what are you doing with my clothes,derek?!
was one time! i know that's what people say.
i know that's what always gets said,but it's--
i don't even know how it happened.
i don't know what i was thinking.
he was just--he was just here.
he was just here.
you screw my best friend,and all you can say--
"he was just here"?
- get out.
- no.
get out. no.
no,i'm not going.
we're gonna just talk about this.
- we're gonna discuss this.
- get out of my house now!
no.no. i'm holding my ground.
- let's go!
- i am holding my ground.
we don't quit!
we have to work-- get out.
what are you doing?
derek! no!
please. please.derek.
please.
please.i'm sorry.i'm sorry.
you have to give me a chance.
you have to give me a chance to show you how rry i am.
i'm sorry,okay? okay.okay?
i'm gonna go.you stay. i'll get my clothes in the morning.
no,no,no,no,no. we can survive this.derek...
we can survive this. we're...
we're addison and derek.
i can't look at you.
i look at you,and i feel nauseous.
i just...
we're not derek and addison anymore.
if you go now...
we are not gonna get through this.
we don't have a chance.
we don't have a chance...
if you go now.
if you go...
hi. uh,you're--
- are you preston burke?
- uh,yes.
the preston burke.
dr.burke,i am such a huge fan.
that stentless valve replacement for infectious endocarditis that you performed?
and your use of transmyocardial revascularization?
i-i'm cristina yang.
if--if i could just get the chance to study under you,i would be...
- you are so amazing!
- yes,well...thank you.
i mean,one of my choices was,uh,san diego.
i coulda gone to san diego.
you know,seattle's home,so...
so you're new to seattle.
oh,no. i-i,um,i kind of live here.
my mother lived here-- lives here--
and i live in her house.
wow,that's great 'cause housing is a nightmare.
i'm living with my,uh,parents at home,
which,uh,well,sucks.
oh,it's nice meeting you.
we've been exposed to the plague.
they don't know it's the plague.
so the men in,uh,white suits,just,what,making a fashion statement?
no,it's a precaution.
when the blood work comes back,we'll be outta here.
what if the results come backand she's,uh,she has the plague?
well,then we get the plagueand then we die in here with the crappy benches
and the dirty scrubsand the lockers full of old food.
there's food in the lockers?
dr.shepherd,those are people's person--that's alex's apple.
that's just rude.
safe haven laws--all those girls would've had to do is
drop that baby off at a fire stationor a hospital.
now...
it's a mess.
what are our options here?
blood typing.
we take a sample from each of the girls.
the baby's blood type is double-o.
if the girls are a or b,it means the baby is not theirs.
do it.
everyone thinks i'll know what tsay to her.
i don't know what to say to her.
dark and twisty meredith.
i'm not dark and twisty.
and if i am dark and twisty,it's because i live my life under a banner of avoidance.
i avoid. i'm an avoider.
hello?
- hey.
so can we,uh--izzie.
i gotta go check on izzie.
don't take it personally.
it's the doctor thing.
what?
four years of high school,four years of college,four years of med school--
by the time we graduate,we're in our late 20s,
and we've never done anything except go to schooland think about science.
time stops.
we're socially retarded.
i mean,look at me.
i'm in love with a guy who won't say he loves me back,
and here i am in his kitchen cooking,just hoping he comes home and notices me.
i'm a total freak.
i'm that girl in the back of the classwho eats her hair.
meredith...
she's 17 years old.
we're all 17 years old.
this is high school with scalpels,finn.
i don't know what to say to you.
when dylan died...
when--when the bomb went off,did you feel like...
what?
like you were moving in slow motion.
he was there and then he wasn't,like i blinked,and he was gone.
i feel like i'm moving in slow motion...
like i'm moving in slow motionand everything around me is...
moving so fast. and i just want to go back...
to when things were normal,when i wasn't "poor izzie
laying on the bathroom floorin her prom dress with her..."
"her dead fiance"
but i am.
so i can't.
and i'm...
just stuck.
and there's all this pressure'cause everyone's hovering around me,
waiting for me to do somethingor say something or
flip out or yellor cry some more,and i'm happy to play my part.
i'm happy to say the lines and do whatever it is
that i'm supposed to be doingif it will make everyone feel more comfortable.
but i don't--i don't know how to do this.
i don't know how to be this person. i don't...
i don't know who this person is.
izzie...
how did this happen?
how did we end up here?
why am i alone?
where is denny?
you're not alone,iz.
trail mix and warm soda--who puts warm soda in their locker?
as usual,cristina's too lazyto stock her locker with food.
oh,now i hit the mother lode.
here,look at this. i got granola,cookies,muffins.
who eats this much?
that's izzie's locker.
she ate a lot. said it kept her energy up.
- eats.
- what?
eats. you said,"ate." "eats," present tense. she didn't die.
feels a little like she did.
she's never comin' back here.
you know...
i don't think she's ever gonna be the same.
you know,there are moments,o'malley,
where all of a sudden,in a split second,your life changes forever.
before you know it,you're somewhere else.
- gentlemen.
- chief.
can we please get outta here now?
no.
a split second...
straightteruila. really?
you argonna be sorry in the morning.
i'm always sorry in the morning.
but tomorrow i start my first day of work,so keep 'em cominghow ya doin'?
how you doin'?
double scotch,single malt,please.
all right.
so... is this a good place to hang out?
i wouldn'tnow. never been here before.
oh,you know what? i haven't either.
first time here. i'm new in town.
i've never been to seattle.
but i got a job,so...
ah,you're ignoring me.
i'm trying to.
you shouldn't ignore me.
why not?
because i'm someone you need to get to know to love.
- really?
- oh,yes.
- so if i know you,i'll love you?
you really like yourself,huh?
just hiding my pain.
so what's your story?
i don't have a story.
i'm just a girl in a bar.
i'm just a guy in a bar.
how do you not know your kid's pregnant?
you love your kids. you want to see the best in them.
okay,then how do you have a babyand then throw it in a trash can?
something happens,and yopanic.
you freeze,and you want to hide itand...
pretend like it didn't happen.
i get that.
- you get that?
- i do.
i just don't get what happens afterward.
i don't get how...
you go back to classand pretend like everything's fine.
everything's not fine.
oh,it's the blood results.
karen and lisa are not a match.
and then there were two.
miranda...
i-i'm feeling better,a lot better.
i think the fever broke,which is good,right?
- that's very good,omar.
- how'giselle?
is she asking for me?
omar,for giselle,being exposed to the plague,it--it complicated... things.
complicated what things?
we did everything we c-could.
no.
i'm so sorry...omar
no.no.no.no.no!
omar.
come on,breathe.
stop! no,no,stop.
he's hyperventilating.
look,i have to go in there!
you can't go in there.
somebody has to go in.
i have to save her.
i have to help her.
let me outta here!
omar,look at me.
omar... look at me!
look,i need you to put your hands against my hand.
come on.
oh,god.
- my beautiful giselle...
- omar,look at my hands.
put your hands on my hands.
come on.
good. good.
okay.
look at me. look at me.
can you tell me my name?
do you remember my name?
- miranda.
that's right.
i want giselle.
i have to save her.
please help.
please...
let me outta here.
i wish i could help you,omar.
i wish i couldturn back the clock and make it yesterday.
you don't know how much i wish that,but,uh...
i can't turn back time.
oh,i shouldn't have let her drive.
she was sick.
i should've taken over.
i know.
come on.
i know. i...
i shoulda taken over,too,but...
we can't go back.
look,even if i could let you outta here,you can't help giselle now,omar.
do you believe in god,miranda?
huh? do you...
do you believe in the afterlife?
i have to believe.
with what i do,omar,i have to believethat when our time comesthat we go to...
a place,a...
a beautiful place,a...
a better place.
omar...
that woman died.
she actually died.
that doesn't mean we will.
- is it hot in here?
- no.
then why am i sweating?
because you're pacing.
no,my pulse is rapid.
because you're still pacing.
here,feel me.
no,i'm not gonna feel you.
- seriously.
- seriously,no.
you know... you're an ass.
you've lived.
you've done things.
and you got the hair and the hot wifeand the beautiful ex-mistress who pines for you.
she's pining for me?
my point is you've lived.
if you die,who cares?
if i die...
what,this is it?
callie told me she loved me. i just sat there.
i mean,i wasn't ready...
but what,now i'm gonna die,and i'm not even gonna get a
chanceto say "i love you" back?
well,do you?
do you love her?
maybe.
eventually...
i could.
yeah,one day,soonish.
"soonish"?
i will love you "soonish"?
you ever tell meredith?
you ever tell her that you love her?
no.
i did.
but...
i...
i'm with callie...
and...
it's different,but...
you should tell her.
even if it's soonish,you should tell her before it's too late.
you mean before i die of the plague?
before somebody else comes along.
that i believe.
oh,uh...
i'm gonna...
i'm gonna leave the room for a period of timefor no reason whatsoever.
i don't know what happened last night...
between you and derek.
finn--and i don't want to know.
all right,we never said that we were exclusive.
but you have plans.
yeah.
well,i didn't say i wasn't pissed off.
i said we weren't exclusive.
that's all i wanted to say.
oh,and,uh,and this--i-i know you think you're scary and damaged.
dark and twisty.
it makes you feel like you don't deserve good things.
but you do.
and derek...
he's bad for you.
but me-- i'm a good thing.
and if there's a race,if there is a-a ring,my hat is in.
i made an appointment for a reason.
i scheduled the timebecause i had something important to say,
and you made me wait.
i have a situation,adele.
- you don't
- i've spent my life waiting,
waiting for you to finish med school,
waiting for you to come home at night,waiting for you to leave that...
woman.
- i'm done waiting.
- adele--
it's time for you to make a choice--me or this hospital.
it's time for you to retire,richard.
there he is.
that's your son.
i want you both to look at him...
because it's not true that you did nothing wrong.
you both are wrong.
you're wrong for covering this up.
you're wrong for lying about it.
you're wrong for letting this little baby,this
sweet,innocent,beautiful little boysuffer like this.
he's dying,and it's your fault.
it's both of your fault.
and the thing is,the truth will come out.
in time,it will come out.
it always does.
it just...
it just does.
and when it does,this baby will be dead.
shannon...
don't tell my mom,okay?
thank you.
thank you for telling the truth.
you--you really don't feel anything?
i only feel like i've been here for a very long time.
i feel like i might be too late.
too late for what?
thank you for your patience and cooperation,doctors.
you'll have to go on a course of antibiotics,but the threat has been contained.
good.
what?
you're free to go.
poor little guy.
the mite he's okay,we have to turn him overto a mother who's goin' to juvieand
grandparents who are so clueless,they didn't even realize their own kid was pregnant.
imagine the kind of childhood he's gonna have.
you can get over a bad childhood.
you can have the worst crap in the world happen to you,
and then you can get over it.
all you gotta do is survive.
hello?
oh,my god.
oh,my god. i was so worried.
but i'm--i'm fine.
i was really,really worried.
yeah,i know. me,too.
george,i really,really love you.
- hi.
uh,i was gonna come over this morning,but,uh--
- i heard--the quarntine.
- yeah.
so... what does this mean?
it means you have a choice.
you have a choice to make.
and i don't want to rush youinto making a decision before you're ready.
this morning,i was gonna come overand i was gonna say--
what i wanted to say was...
but now all i can say is that...
i'm in love with you.
i've been in love with you for...
ever.
i'm a little late.
i know i'm a little late in telling you that.
i-i just...
i just want you to take your time...
you know?
take all the time you need.
because you have...
a choice to make.
and when i had a choice to make...
i chose wrong.
all right. good night.
time flies.
you're not going to retire,are you?
adele,you spring this on me today.
i-i need more time.
i don't have any more time to give.
time waits for no man.
time heals all wounds.
where have you been all day?
sitting shivah for denny.
- how are you?
oh.
don't ever die.
i'll do my best.
all any of us wants  is more time...
good night.
isn't this so cool?
i mean,can you believe it?
tomorrow,we're gonna be surgeons.
time to stand up...
time to grow up...
i'm ready.
okay.
time to let go...
time.